Dr. Ashik Ali Lakhani

B.D.S, M.D.S (ENDODONTIST)



Experienced Endodontist with a demonstrated history of working in the medical practice industry. Skilled in Dentistry, Single visit Endodontics, Public Speaking, Teeth Whitening, tooth jewellery, Healthcare, and Healthcare Management. Strong consulting professional with a Master of dental surgery (M.D.S) focused in Conservative dentistry and Endodontics.

RUNGTA COLLEGE OF DENTAL SCIENCE AND RESEARCH INSTITUTE BHILAI (C.G)

JUNE 2014 - August 2017

EDUCATION

M.D.S (MASTER OF DENTAL SURGERY)

- Underwent 6 months training in pre-clinical postings
- During this period was actively involved in chair side teaching to undergraduate students.
- \bullet Two year clinical posting perfomed all the clinical cases under the scope of Conservative & Endodontics such as-
- All the restorative procedures using various materials like amalgam, composites & G.I.C etc
- Cast metal Restorations like inlay, onlay.
- Root canal treatments with all the variations in techniques & materials.
- Special Endo cases like 3MB Canals, 2Palatal canals etc.
- Endodontic Mishaps or Procedural Accidents Cases like Bypass of separated instruments, ledge bypass, instrument retrieval, Perforation Repair.
- Treatment & follow up of various traumatic injuries including avulsions, crown, root fractures of teeth using splinting, re-attachment & vital pulp therapies
- Post endodontic restorative procedures using custom made metal / pre-fabricated metal esthetic posts.
- Cosmetic Procedures like Bleaching, Veneering, Endocrowns
- Endo- Perio Cases
- Splinting and Crown Lengthening
- Surgeries like Periapical surgery, hemisection, resoption repair with MTA and Biodentin.
- Vital & non vital crowns & bridges using metal alloys, P.F.M, & all ceramic materials
- Presented seminars, case presentations and journal clubs on various topics ranging from basic sciences to Advanced Conservative & Endodontics.
- Lectures for undergraduate students on Advanced Conservative & Endodontics.

RUNGTA COLLEGE OF DENTAL SCIENCE AND RESEARCH INSTITUTE BHILAI (C.G)

SEPT - 2007 - 2013

B.D.S (BACHELOR OF DENTAL SURGERY)

2007–2012: Underwent training in all branches of general dentistry for a period of BDS four years that included training in subjects pertaining to General Anatomy, Physiology, Microbiology, Pathology, General Medicine and Surgery. Performed under supervision general dentistry procedures like dental extractions, management of medically compromised patients, dental restorations, fabrication of partial and complete dentures.

2012-2013: Underwent a one-year compulsory rotatory housemanship in all the fields of dentistry. Performed independently under supervision all the routine procedures in dentistry, which included rehabilitation of complete and partially edentulous patients, conservative dentistry and endodontic and periodontics. Attended treatment camps at rural health centres as a part of the rotation.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer Consultantion Ahmedabad

01-12-2019 - Presently working

Consultant Endodontist (self Employed)

- Going for consultant for Endodontic case in private clinics
- Assigned the tasks of examining, diagnosing and treating diseases of nerve, pulp, and other dental tissues.
- Examined teeth and gums by using dental instruments, x -ray and other diagnostic equipment.
- Handled the tasks of treating exposure of pulp by pulp capping or removal of pulp from pulp chamber and root canal by using dental instruments.

CONSULTANT ENDODONTIST

- Handling Endodontic case in more than 9 branch.
- Assigned the tasks of examining, diagnosing and treating diseases of nerve, pulp, and other

Clove Dental Hospital hyderabad

02/04/2018 - 30-11-2019

dental tissues.

- Examined teeth and gums by using dental instruments, x -ray and other diagnostic equipment.
- Handled the tasks of treating exposure of pulp by pulp capping or removal of pulp from pulp chamber and root canal by using dental instruments.
- Performed total or partial removal of pulp with the help of surgical instruments.
- Treated infected root canal and fills pulp chamber and canal with endodontic materials.
- Performed bleaching discolored teeth to restore natural color.
- Responsible for evaluating findings and prescribing methods of treatment to prevent loss of teeth and to restore the function of teeth.
- Assigned the tasks of traveling to multiple offices in the region to perform specialized clinical treatments.
- Maintained good relationships with professional groups, dental associations and dental societies to represent Alba in the local community.
- Performed other related tasks as required

Scientific Archives of Dental Sciences (SAODS)

2019 - Present

Editorial board member (SAODS JOURNAL)

Editors are requested to screen the manuscript and express their view with regards to article whether it falls under the scope of journal or not and requested to check the desired publication criteria.

Editors are requested to screen the reviewer comments and monitor the complete peer review process to maintain the standard of the journal.

Editors are requested to take complete responsibility to accept/reject an article for publication.

Editorial board member should comply with ethics and maintain confidentiality with regards to submitted articles.

Editors should participate actively in peer review process and editorial activities.

As an editor to conduct special issues, editions based on expertise and research interest.

Editors are requested to maintain highest possible standards of Technical and Professional quality of journal submissions.

Partha dental hospital hyderabad

03/09/2017 - 01/03/2018

CONSULTANT ENDODONTIST

- Treated patients with endodontic problems by adhering to the highest standard of dental practice ethics and professionalism
- Examined, diagnosed and treated diseases of dental pulps and periapical tissues of teeth
- Responsible for evaluating findings and prescribing methods of treatment to prevent loss of teeth and to restore the function of teeth
- Assigned the tasks of traveling to multiple offices in the region to perform specialized clinical treatments
- Maintained good relationships with professional groups, dental associations and dental societies to represent Alba in the local community
- Performed other related tasks as required

The Cosmos Dental Hospital hyderabad

Sept 2017 - Sept 2018

CONSULTANT ENDODONTIST (PART TIME)

- 1) Examine, diagnosis, and treats disease of neevr, pulp, and other dental tissues affecting vitality of teeth
- 2) Examine teeth, gums and related tissues to define conditio, using dental instrumens, x-ray and other diagnostic equipment.
- 3) Diagnosis condition plans treatment.
- 4) Treat exposure of pulp by pulp cappping or removal of pulp from pulp chmaber root canal, using dental instrument.
- 5) Perform partial or total removal of pulp, using surgical instrument.
- 6) Treat infected root canal and related tissues, fills pulp chmaber canal with endodontic materials.
- 7) Remove pathologic tissue at alrx of tooth, surgically.
- 8) Reinsert teeth that have been knocked out of mouth by accident.
- 9) Bleack discolored teeth to restore natual color.

10) Conduct x-rays and other dental test to find out the dental problem.

11) Needs to be updated with the latest in this field.

LAVANYA DENTAL HOSPITAL SECUNDERABAD

OCT-2013 - MAY-2014

DENTIST

- Diagnoses and treats diseases and malformations of teeth and associated structures in the jaw and mouth using surgery and other specialist techniques
- Plan oral health care in consultation with patients
- Perform tasks of cleaning teeth and cavities and provide preventive care, such as scaling and fluoride therapy
- Handle tasks of repairing decayed and broken teeth by rebuilding tooth structures
- Conduct routine surgical procedures, like extracting teeth, as well as complex operations on soft tissues and the jaws
- Administer local anesthetics, if required for carrying out treatment

Skills

PROFESSIONAL STRENGTH

- Ability to perform simple molar root canals and complex root canals of all teeth
- Possess extensive knowledge of surgical endodontics and one visit root canal treatment procedures
- Ability to work within a multinational workforce in an effective way
- Possess sound oral and written communication skills
- Ability to generate treatment plans and prescribe medications to ease pain
- Flexibility, multi tasking with excellent organizational skills

AREA OF INTEREST

- To use my skills in examining, diagnosing, and providing treatment counseling to patients in a comprehensive manner
- To provide the best treatment to a variety of patients with conditions affecting the pulp and roots of teeth

AFFILIATIONS

Madhya Pradesh state dental council

Member of the Indian dental Association

Member of Indian academy of conservative dentistry and endodontics

ADVANCED TRAINING PROGRAMMES ATTENDED

- Attended CDE program on "Unlocking neoplasia: A novel approach" held at Rungta College of Dental Sciences & Research, Bhilai on 9th Jan' 2015.
- Attended CDE program on "Current and future trends in oral implantology" 9th February 2016, Bhilai.
- Attended Live surgical demonstration on "Dental implant" 1st August 2015, Rungta College of Dental Sciences and Research, Bhilai.
- Attended CDE program on "CAD-CAM in prosthodontics", 11th September 2015, in Bhilai.
- Attended CDE program on "Full mouth rehabilitation", 28th January 2016, in Bhilai.
- Attended CDE program on "Current trends of laser in restorative dentistry" 22nd April 2016.
- Attended lecture on "Orofacial pain: A dentist's dilemma" 27th February 2017.
- Attended CDE programme on "Dentistry today: Reasons to smile" 16th January 2017.

PUBLICATIONS

Efficacy of Triple Antibiotic Paste, Moxifloxacin, Calcium Hydroxide And 2% Chlorhexidine Gel In Elimination of E. Faecalis: An In vitro Study. journal of clinical and diagnostic research 2017.

Publication Url:

http://www.jcdr.net/pdf_download.asp?issn=0973-709x&year=2017&month=January&volume=11&issue=1&page=ZC06&id=9132

Evaluation of Microleakage with Total Etch, Self Etch and Universal Adhesive Systems in Class V Restorations: An In vitro Study. journal of clinical and diagnostic research 2017.

Publication Url:

http://www.jcdr.net/pdf_download.asp?issn=0973-709x&year=2017&month=April&volume=11&issue=4&page=ZC53&id=9680

KNOWLEDGE AND ATTITUDE OF ENDODONTIC UNDERGRADUATE STUDENTS TOWARD STERILIZATION OF ENDODONTIC FILES: A CROSS-SECTIONAL STUDY. International Journal of Research in Health and Allied Sciences 2017.

Publication Url:

http://ijrhas.com/uploadfiles/8%20o%20Sterilization%20of%20endodontic%20files.2017021508 1111.pdf

BIOCERAMICS IN OPERATIVE DENTISTRY AND ENDODONTICS. International Journal of Medical and Oral Research 2016.

Publication Url: http://ijmor.com/uploads/aa-1.pdf

MALIGNANT HEMANGIOPERICYTOMA OF PALATE- A CASE REPORT. Journal of Advanced Medical and Dental Sciences Research 2016.

Publication Url: http://www.jamdsr.com/uploadfiles/27%20hemangiopericytoma.20161008092406.pdf

RESEARCH ACTIVITIES

Dissertation: A comparative clinical evaluation between different generations apex locators with digital radiography of patients at different age groups

Library Dissertation: smart material in restorative dentistry

COMMUNITY SERVICE

Conducted various free ORAL HEALTH CHECK UP CAMPS and awareness camps at rural, urban and suburban areas.

KEYS FOR SUCCESS

Integrity, Ethics, Leadership, Teamwork, Training, Recognition, Communication and Continuous improvement

REFERENCES

Dr.Pradeep Tavane Dean and Prof Head of Department of Conservative & Endodontics Rungta College of Dental Science & Research Kurud Road,Kohka, Bhilai Chattisgarh,INDIA Phone No. +919845054808,

Dr. Pankaj kr Gupta Reader Conservative & Endodontics Rungta College of Dental Science & Research Kurud Road,Kohka, Bhilai Chattisgarh,INDIA

Phone No. +91 90742 47173